export const data = [
  {
    id: "01",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "Who played an important role in international human rights law?",
    options: [
      "Economic summit",
      "World War",
      "The United Nations",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "The United Nations",
    description:
      "The United Nations has played an important role in international human rights law.",
  },
  {
    id: "02",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "The Universal declaration of human rights is applicable to?",
    options: [
      "Every individual, regardless of religion, race, gender, or cultural background",
      "The citizens of UN member countries",
      "Some countries",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer:
      "Every individual, regardless of religion, race, gender, or cultural background",
    description:
      "The Universal declaration of human rights is applicable to every individual regardless of religion, race, gender, or cultural background.",
  },
  {
    id: "03",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "When is International Human Rights Day?",
    options: ["8 March", " 3 September", "10 December", "6 July"],
    answer: "10 December",
    description:
      "Human Rights Day is the day in 1948 the United Nations General Assembly adopted the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. 2023 is the 75th anniversary. 2023 Theme: Dignity, Freedom, and Justice for All.",
  },
  {
    id: "04",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which article of the universal declaration of human rights tells that the right of nationality depends on one's wish?",
    options: ["Article 10", "Article 20", "Article 15", "Article 30"],
    answer: "Article 15",
    description:
      "Article 15 of the Universal Declaration of human rights states that - 'Everyone has the right to a nationality.' 'No one shall be arbitrarily deprived of his nationality nor denied the right to change his nationality.'",
  },
  {
    id: "05",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "Which African country was never a European colony?",
    options: ["Kenya", "Uganda", "Ethiopia", "Nigeria"],
    answer: "Ethiopia",
    description:
      "Ethiopia, the only sub-Saharan African country that was never colonized by European states.",
  },
  {
    id: "06",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "How many countries have laws ban abortion?",
    options: ["28", "32", "16", "20"],
    answer: "28",
    description:
      "28 countries around the world have laws which completely ban abortion even in cases where a woman’s life or health is in danger and in cases of rape.",
  },
  {
    id: "07",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "What is the full form of UNHCR?",
    options: [
      "United Nations high commissioner for refugees",
      "United Nations high-level committee for refugees",
      "United Nations health committee for refugees",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "United Nations high commissioner for refugees",
    description:
      "UNHCR is also known as the UN refugee agency. It was created in 1950 to help the millions of Europeans who have lost their homes during the Second World War.",
  },
  {
    id: "08",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "What are civil and political rights?",
    options: [
      "Economic equality, Personal freedoms and protection from discrimination, Access to education, Environmental protection",
      "Right to privacy, free speech and healthcare",
      "Freedom to join with others in peaceful assembly and association",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
    description:
      "The United Nations has played an important role in international human rights law.",
  },
  {
    id: "09",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "By May of 2023, how many people were displaced worldwide due to conflict, persecution, human rights violations, and violence?",
    options: ["90 million", "65.3 million", "110 million", "80 million"],
    answer: "110 million",
    description:
      "More than 110 million by May 2023, includes: 35.3 million refugees, 62.5 million internally displaced people, 5.4 million asylum seekers, 5.2 million people in need of international protection.",
  },
  {
    id: "10",
    category: "General",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "The Universal declaration of human rights was adopted under whose chairmanship?",
    options: [
      "Adolf Hitler",
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Eleanor Roosevelt",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Eleanor Roosevelt",
    description:
      "Eleanor Roosevelt was an American political figure and also served as the first lady of the United States. Eleanor Roosevelt was the first chairperson of the commission on human rights (CHR).",
  },
  {},
  {
    id: "11",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "Which was the first country to allow women to vote?",
    options: ["USA", "New Zealand", "UK", "None of the above"],
    answer: "New Zealand",
    description: "New Zealand(1893)",
  },
  {
    id: "12",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Who is a British chemist who was instrumental in discovering the structure of DNA. A rover went to Mars in 2021 bears her name.",
    options: [
      "Rosalind Franklin",
      "Dorothy Hodgkin",
      "Edith Humphrey",
      "Hertha Ayrton",
    ],
    answer: "Rosalind Franklin",
    description:
      "Dr. Rosalind Franklin is a British scientist. She successfully used X-ray on fibers of DNA to capture the famous photo that proved DNA is a double helix.",
  },
  {
    id: "13",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "In what way does feminism challenge mainstream security studies?",
    options: [
      "By campaigning for women to be allowed to be soldiers",
      "By broadening the notion of security away from just looking at the nation-state and militarism",
      "By acknowledging that men are naturally aggressive and have a higher propensity to encourage conflict",
      "By campaigning for peace",
    ],
    answer:
      "By broadening the notion of security away from just looking at the nation-state and militarism",
    description:
      "Feminism challenges mainstream security studies by critiquing the traditional focus on military and state-centric security.",
  },
  {
    id: "14",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Worldwide, what share of seats in national parliaments are held by women in 2023?",
    options: ["26.5%", "5%", "10.4%", "40%"],
    answer: "26.5%",
    description:
      "Worldwide, women's overall share of seats rose by just 0.4 percentage points to 26.5%, the slowest growth in six years.",
  },
  {
    id: "15",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "Which country has the most female representation in parliament?",
    options: ["USA", "Sweden", "UK", "Rwanda"],
    answer: "Rwanda",
    description:
      "In Rwanda, women hold more than 60% of seats and which in 2008 became the first country to have a female-majority parliament.",
  },
  {
    id: "16",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Across the world, women do more unpaid care and domestic work than men. How much more?",
    options: [
      "50% more",
      "Around three times more",
      "Around twice as much",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Around three times more",
    description:
      "Women typically spend disproportionately more time on unpaid care work than men. On account of gendered social norms that view unpaid care work as a female prerogative, women across different regions, socio-economic classes and cultures spend an important part of their day on meeting the expectations of their domestic and reproductive roles.",
  },
  {
    id: "17",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "In their lives, how many women will experience physical or sexual abuse?",
    options: ["1 in 3", "1 in 2", "1 in 5", "1 in 10"],
    answer: "1 in 3",
    description:
      "1 in 3 women have experienced physical or sexual violence – mostly by an intimate partner.",
  },
  {
    id: "18",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "On average, what percentage of women are paid less than men?",
    options: ["20.3%", "22.2%", "10%", "24%"],
    answer: "24%",
    description:
      "Globally, women are paid 24 per cent less than men for comparable work, across all regions and sectors. At the current rate of progress, it will take 170 years to close the pay gap.",
  },
  {
    id: "19",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "How many countries have laws that prevent women from working in some jobs as men?",
    options: ["104", "82", "65", "None of the above."],
    answer: "104",
    description:
      "104 countries have laws that prevent women from working in some jobs, this means that over 2.7 billion women are legally restricted from having the same employment choices as men.",
  },
  {
    id: "20",
    category: "Gender Equality",
    type: "boolean",
    question:
      "Over 95 Oscars ceremonies, only 5 women have ever won the Academy Award for Best Director.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    description:
      "Only 3 woman, Kathryn Bigelow for The Hurt Locker in 2010, Chloé Zhao for Nomadland in 2021, Jane Campion for The Power of The Dog in 2022",
  },
  {
    id: "21",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "boolean",
    question:
      "Federal law protects gay and transgender individuals from all forms of discrimination.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    description:
      "There is no federal law explicitly prohibiting discrimination based on sexual orientation or gender identity. Several federal courts, however, have concluded that LGBT people are protected from discrimination under current federal laws that prohibit discrimination based on sex.",
  },
  {
    id: "22",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "When did the first protest for gay rights in Washington, D.C. occur?",
    options: ["1955", "1975", "1965", "1985"],
    answer: "1965",
    description:
      "It took place on April 17, 1965 after news broke that Cuba was putting gays into labor camps.",
  },
  {
    id: "23",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "In what city did the Stonewall riots break out on June, 28, 1969, the start of the gay rights movement?",
    options: ["Miami", "Washington D.C.", "San Francisco", "NYC"],
    answer: "NYC",
    description:
      "The disturbance began after police raided the Stonewall Inn in New York City.",
  },
  {
    id: "24",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Whose murder spurred Congress to pass legislation, later vetoed by President George W. Bush, that would have protected gays under federal hate-crime laws?",
    options: [
      "Matthew Shepard",
      "Jane Shepard",
      "Jack Shepard",
      "Alan Shepard",
    ],
    answer: "Matthew Shepard",
    description:
      "In 1998, the University of Wyoming student Matthew Shepard was tortured, tied to a fence and murdered because of his sexual orientation, which brought national and international attention to hate crime legislation.",
  },
  {
    id: "25",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "What was the first country to legalise same-sex marriage?",
    options: ["USA", "Denmark", "Sweden", "Germany"],
    answer: "Denmark",
    description:
      "The Danish were the first to grant same-sex unions almost the exact same rights as marriages, with its Registered Partnerships Act of 1989. However, the law stopped short of calling same-sex unions 'marriages,' and couples could not be married in the Danish state church or adopt a child.  Even so, the law was viewed as an important stepping stone at the time.",
  },
  {
    id: "26",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "When is pride month?",
    options: ["March", "June", "July", "August"],
    answer: "June",
    description:
      "The concept of Pride Month began with the Stonewall riots, a series of riots for gay liberation that took place over several days beginning on June 28, 1969.",
  },
  {
    id: "27",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which gay Harlem Renaissance writer was honored as a commander in the French Legion of Honor?",
    options: [
      "James Baldwin",
      "Bayard Rustin",
      "Lorraine Hansberry",
      "Audre Lorde",
    ],
    answer: "James Baldwin",
    description:
      "Baldwin was made a Commander of the French Legion of Honor in June of 1986.",
  },
  {
    id: "28",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "What was the name of the Oscar-winning movie from 2005 about two gay cowboys?",
    options: [
      "The Magnificent Seven",
      "Pale Rider",
      "Brokeback Mountain",
      "Blazing Saddles",
    ],
    answer: "Brokeback Mountain",
    description:
      "It is directed by Ang lee follows the lives of two men as they struggle to come to terms with their sexuality.",
  },
  {
    id: "29",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "What TV show featured the largest transgender cast in history?",
    options: ["Pose", "Fiends", "Gossip Girl", "Sense 8"],
    answer: "Pose",
    description:
      "Pose is a deep dive into the New York ball scene of the late Eighties – an underground subculture in which LGBT+ people (largely of colour) competed, as part of “houses”, in dance and drag competitions.",
  },
  {
    id: "30",
    category: "LGBTQ+ Rights",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Who is the famous English singer and pianist, famous for hits such as “Your Song”? He is an avid campaigner for LGBTQ+ rights and against HIV/AIDS?",
    options: ["Elton John", "Lady Gaga", "Tom Cook", "Oscar Wilde"],
    answer: "Elton John",
    description:
      "The Elton John AIDS Foundation (EJAF) is a nonprofit organization, established by musician Sir Elton John in 1992 in the United States and 1993 in the United Kingdom to support innovative HIV prevention, education programs, direct care and support services to people living with or at risk of HIV.",
  },
  {
    id: "31",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "boolean",
    question:
      "In more authoritarian states, Covid-19 restrictions were a convenient tool for government to use to restrict rights to protest and dissent.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    description:
      "The 2021 Global Expression Report found: ‘two-thirds of the world’s population – 4.9 billion people – are living in countries that are highly restricted in freedom of expression or in crisis: more than at any time in the last decade.’",
  },
  {
    id: "32",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Who is the person got missing in Wuhan, China in May 2020 and still under goverment's control?",
    options: ["Xu Zhiyong", "Zhang Zhan", "Ding Jiaxi", "Chang Weiping"],
    answer: "Zhang Zhan",
    description:
      "Zhang Zhan is a citizen journalist who reported on Covid-19 when it first appeared in Wuhan, China. She went missing in May 2020. She had been taken by the Chinese authorities and sentenced to four years in prison for “picking quarrels and provoking trouble”.",
  },
  {
    id: "33",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "Which of the following is a means of forced ethnic change?",
    options: [
      "Cultural persecution",
      "Mass detention and expulsion",
      "Directed settlement",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
    description:
      "Governments and occupying powers in 21 countries and territories use a variety of methods to deliberately change their ethnic composition so as to destroy a culture or tip the political balance.",
  },
  {
    id: "34",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which country was suspended from the UN Human Rights Council in 2022?",
    options: ["China", "Russia", "Saudi Arabia", "Belarus"],
    answer: "Russia",
    description:
      "The council also appointed a special rapporteur to monitor the human rights situation in the country.",
  },
  {
    id: "35",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "The worst countries for internet censorship?",
    options: [
      "North Korea and China",
      "Iran, Myanmar, Turkmenistan, and UAE",
      "Syria",
      "Pakistan",
    ],
    answer: "North Korea and China",
    description:
      "All of the political media published in the country is heavily censored and influenced by the government. Both also shut down messaging apps from abroad, forcing residents to use ones that have been made (and are likely controlled) within the country, e.g. WeChat in China.",
  },
  {
    id: "36",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "As established by the ECtHR case law, freedom of expression protects:",
    options: [
      "Only literatures",
      "Only journalists’ works",
      "The form in which ideas are expressed and substance of ideas",
      "Only creative works",
    ],
    answer: "The form in which ideas are expressed and substance of ideas",
    description: "",
  },
  {
    id: "37",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which country is known for its 'Great Firewall,' which restricts citizens' access to international websites and social media platforms?",
    options: ["Denmark", "China", "USA", "Japan"],
    answer: "China",
    description:
      "It is the combination of legislative actions and technologies enforced by China to regulate the Internet domestically. Its role in internet censorship in China is to block access to selected foreign websites and to slow down cross-border internet traffic.",
  },
  {
    id: "38",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which one is the most dangerous country for journalists in 2022?",
    options: ["China", "Haiti", "Mexico", "Brazil"],
    answer: "Mexico",
    description:
      "Data from an industry report revealed that the most dangerous country for journalists in 2022 was Mexico, with 11 killed there that year. Ukraine came a close second with eight journalists killed, partly as a result of the war.",
  },
  {
    id: "39",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "When is International Human Rights Day?",
    options: ["8 March", "3 September", "10 December", "6 July"],
    answer: "10 December",
    description:
      "Human Rights Day is the day in 1948 the United Nations General Assembly adopted the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. 2023 is the 75th anniversary. 2023 Theme: Dignity, Freedom, and Justice for All.",
  },
  {
    id: "40",
    category: "Freedom of Expression",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which country has the Most Freedom of Speech/Expression in 2022?",
    options: ["Ireland", "Norway", "Denmark", "Portugal"],
    answer: "Norway",
    description:
      "Norway is ranked No.1 in 2022 in terms of freedom of speech. It is evaluated against five distinct categories: political context, legal framework, economic context, sociocultural context and safety.",
  },
  {
    id: "41",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which event is the basis for the annual commemoration of the International Day for the Elimination of Racial Discrimination?",
    options: [
      "Nelson Mandela’s release from prison",
      "The killing of demonstrators in Sharpeville, South Africa",
      "The first multi-racial elections in South Africa",
    ],
    answer: "The killing of demonstrators in Sharpeville, South Africa",
    description:
      "The International Day for the Elimination of Racial Discrimination is observed annually on the day the police in Sharpeville, South Africa, opened fire and killed 69 people at a peaceful demonstration against apartheid in 1960. In 1979, the General Assembly adopted a programme of activities to be undertaken during the second half of the Decade for Action to Combat Racism and Racial Discrimination.",
  },
  {
    id: "42",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "boolean",
    question: "Worldwide, Covid-19 leads to more Anti-Asian hate crimes.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    description:
      "The compilation of hate crime data, published by the Center for the Study of Hate and Extremism, revealed that anti-Asian hate crime increased by 339 percent last year compared to the year before, with New York, San Francisco, Los Angeles and other cities surpassing their record numbers in 2020.",
  },
  {
    id: "43",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "What Are microaggressions?",
    options: [
      "When I look at you, I don’t see color",
      "Think black people are loud/animated/aggressive when they speak",
      "You aren’t like the other Asian people I know",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
    description:
      "A: Colour blindness (e.g. statements that indicate that a White person does not want to or need to acknowledge race). B: Denigrating cultural values/communication styles (e.g. the notion that the values and communication styles of the dominant/White culture are ideal/normal). C: Indicating the person is different from the stereotypes of Asian people.",
  },
  {
    id: "44",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Who is the person that got murdered while waiting for a bus in London in 1993?",
    options: [
      "Christopher Alaneme",
      "Stephen Lawrence",
      "Bijan Ebrahimi",
      "Ahmaud Arbery",
    ],
    answer: "Stephen Lawrence",
    description:
      "Stephen Lawrence (13 September 1974 – 22 April 1993) was a black British teenager from Plumstead, southeast London, who was murdered in a racially motivated attack while waiting for a bus in Well Hall Road, Eltham on the evening of 22 April 1993, when he was 18 years old.",
  },
  {
    id: "45",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Approximately how many Africans became victims of the transatlantic slave trade?",
    options: ["21 million", "15 million", "7 million", "10 million"],
    answer: "15 million",
    description:
      "For over 400 years, more than 15 million men, women and children were the victims of the transatlantic slave trade. It is estimated that one-third of the 15 million people who were sold as slaves from Africa were women. In addition to enduring the harsh conditions of slavery, they experienced extremely cruel forms of discrimination and sexual violence and exploitation because of their gender and skin color.",
  },
  {
    id: "46",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question: "When is the Black History Month in the US?",
    options: ["February", "May", "September", "June"],
    answer: "February",
    description:
      "It is a celebration of the African diaspora including, African-American history, and is held in February in the US and Canada, while in Ireland and the UK it's in October.",
  },
  {
    id: "47",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which landmark U.S. Supreme Court case upheld the constitutionality of 'separate but equal' facilities under Jim Crow Laws?",
    options: [
      "Brown v. Board of Education",
      "Plessy v. Ferguson",
      "Loving v. Virginia",
      "Roe v. Wade",
    ],
    answer: "Plessy v. Ferguson",
    description:
      "On May 18, 1896, the U.S. Supreme Court case Plessy v. Ferguson ruled that separate-but-equal facilities were constitutional. The Plessy v. Ferguson decision upheld the principle of racial segregation over the next half-century.",
  },
  {
    id: "48",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "In what church were four young Black girls killed and 20 people wounded when a bomb planted by Ku Klux Klan members exploded in September 1963?",
    options: [
      "16th Street Baptist Church in Birmingham, Alabama",
      "Ebenezer Baptist Church in Atlanta",
      "Shiloh Baptist Church in Byhalia, Mississippi",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "16th Street Baptist Church in Birmingham, Alabama",
    description:
      "Cynthia Wesley, Addie Mae Collins, Denise McNair and Carol Robertson were killed in the 1963 bombing. Birmingham Post-Herald.",
  },
  {
    id: "49",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "multiple",
    question:
      "Which nationality was the first to be banned from moving to the United States?",
    options: ["Chinese", "Japanese", "Mexican", "Nigerian"],
    answer: "Chinese",
    description:
      "Signed on May 6, 1882, the Chinese Exclusion Act was the first U.S. immigration law that specifically targeted an ethnic group on grounds of public order. The law provided an absolute ban on entry into the United States by Chinese laborers, who had previously helped build the transcontinental railroad and mined across the West.",
  },
  {
    id: "50",
    category: "Anti-racism",
    type: "boolean",
    question: "Racism in European Countries is mostly a thing of the past.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    description:
      "While progress has been made, racial discrimination remains a concern in Europe. According to the European Union Agency for Fundamental Rights (FRA) survey in 2020, around 30% of respondents from ethnic minority groups reported experiencing racial harassment, and over 50% felt discriminated against when seeking employment. This data underscores the ongoing challenges in achieving full racial equality in European countries.",
  },
];
